<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Yeng</string>

    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home">News and Updates</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">Yeng</string>
    <string name="openDrawer">Open</string>
    <string name="closeDrawer">Close</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="admissionRules"  formatted="false" >
        \n
        \n
        A). Eligibility for admission to the B.Tech., programme, admission policy and procedure
shall be decided from time to time by following the guidelines issued by the
Government of Kerala and the Government of India and other statutory body such
as AICTE.
        \n
        \n
B). Subject to Clause 1(a), Admission to B.Tech., shall be based on the guidelines given
by the State and Central Governments on reservation. Candidates for admission to
B.Tech., programme shall have passed the Higher Secondary Examination, Kerala or
12th Standard V.H.S.E., C.B.S.E., I.S.C or any other examination considered equivalent
to the above mentioned ones. Other eligibility criteria for admission is currently
prescribed by the Government of Kerala through Government orders which is based
on the entrance examination conducted by the Commission for Entrance
Examinations, Government of Kerala and the marks in the qualifying examination
subject to the relaxations allowed for backward classes and other communities as
specified from time to time.
        \n
        \n
C). The Branches of study and number of students admitted are to be based on the
approval by the All India Council for Technical Education and the Kerala
Technological University.
        \n
        \n
D). Notwithstanding all that is stated above, the admission policy may be modified from
time to time by the University, particularly to confirm to directions from the
Government of Kerala and the Government of India.
        \n
        \n
4). The B.Tech., / B.Tech. (Honours) programme is a credit based programme. The
duration of the B. Tech / B. Tech (Honours) programme will normally be four
academic years spanning 8 semesters. The maximum duration shall be six academic
years spanning 12 semesters.
        \n
        \n
    </string>
    <string name="examinationRules"  formatted="false" >
        \n
        A). At the end of the semester, end semester examination will be conducted in all
lecture based courses offered in the semester and will normally be of three hours
duration, unless otherwise specified. Supplementary examinations shall be
conducted before the commencement of the next semester, for students who are
eligible and have registered for them.
        \n
        \n
B). Students, who have completed a course but could not write the end semester
examination for valid reasons like illness or personal exigencies, are allowed to write
the supplementary examination or the end semester examination at the next
opportunity and earn the credits without having to register for the course again
provided they meet other eligibility criteria.
        \n
        \n
C). The main eligibility criteria for the end semester examination are attendance in the
course, internal marks and no pending disciplinary action. The minimum attendance
for appearing for the end semester examination is 75% in each course. Further, the
internal evaluation marks in the course should be 45% or above. Students who do
not meet these eligibility criteria are awarded an FE grade and have to register for
the course again.
        \n
        \n
D). Students who could not write the end semester examination due to health reasons
or other exigencies can register for the supplementary examination, with the
approval of the principal provided they have 45% or above marks in the internal
evaluations for the course. Candidates who received F grade can also write the
supplementary examination. Grades awarded in the supplementary examination will
be taken as the end semester grades in these courses.
        \n
        \n
    </string>
    <string name="eligibilityrules">
        \n
        The award of B. Tech. / B. Tech. (Honours) degree shall be based on the
recommendation of the Academic Committee and the approval of the Board of
Governors and in accordance with the academic regulations, if any, issued for the said
purpose by the University.
Award of B. Tech. Degree
        \n
        \n
A student will be eligible for the award of B. Tech. Degree of the University on
satisfying the following requirements.
        \n
i) Earned credits for all the core courses and the Project.
        \n
ii) Earned the required minimum credits as specified in the curriculum for the
branch of study.
        \n
iii) No pending disciplinary action.

    </string>
    <string name="feesrules">
        \n

        Fee charged for the programme shall be decided by the University from time to time
and informed to all concerned for compliance.
        \n
    </string>
    <string name="discipline">
        \n
        Every college shall have a Student’s Welfare Committee and a Disciplinary Action
Committee, constituted by the Principal of the college. Each college should have a
Grievance Redressal and Appeals Committee constituted by the Principal to address
the grievances of the students and to consider their appeals on any decisions made by
the college. Details on the constitution and terms of reference are outlined in 7-x, 7-y,
and 7-z
        \n
    </string>
    <string name="guidlineRules"></string>
</resources>
